o2blueroom.co.uk 2006-04-09

# O2: The leading mobile phone site on the Web

Contents  

  1. Introduction
  2. How We Collect Information
  3. What Information do we collect ?
  4. Why we collect information?
  5. Disclosure of Your Information
  6. Co-branded_Toc82333630 microsites and third party sites
  7. Cookies
  8. Accessing Your Information
  9. Security
  10. Users under 16
  11. Changes to this policy
  12. FAQs on related issues
  13. Glossary

1\. Introduction  
O2 (UK) Limited (referred to in this policy as "we", "us "and "O2" ) takes your privacy very seriously. This policy explains how we collect and use information about you when you use our Web and WAP sites and the ways in which we may use that information such as to enhance the services we offer to you and to improve your online experience. It also sets out details of the personal information we collect about you and the ways in which we may use that information and also provides other information such as details about cookies and how to update or access any personal information we hold about you.  
You should read this policy in conjunction with O2 Web and WAP services terms & conditions and your standard airtime contract as well as any other product/service terms that you have been notified about.

Link to Glossary

Back to Top

2\. How We Collect Information

We collect information about you in two ways:

**i) Directly from you**  
From time to time you will be asked to, or will need to, provide personal details about yourself, such as when: 

  * You shop on this site;
  * You register to become an O2 customer
  * You submit enquiries to us/contact us
  * You enter any online promotions, competitions or prize draws via wap or web
  * You use O2 products and services
  * You submit information to us by participating in O2 surveys

**ii) Indirectly from you, such as when:**

  * You visit/ browse this site (see section 6, Cookies) 
  * You visit/browse O2 group websites;

We may also employ third parties to provide website services on our behalf. In such cases, if they collect any data on their own behalf, they will provide their own privacy policy. We advise you to read any new policy carefully. We do, however, endeavour to ensure that any partners we use apply the same high standards of privacy and security over your information. Link to Glossary 

3\. What Information do we collect?  
In various areas of this website we ask you for information. This may include such information as your name, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, your use of products and services, debit or credit card details and other payment information. For example:  

  * When you place a sales order with us we need to know your name, e-mail address, delivery address, credit or debit card number and expiry date or banking details, as appropriate. This enables us to process your order
  * We might ask you if you want to enter a competition or promotion. For this we will usually ask for an e-mail address and/or mobile phone number
  * We may ask you for information about yourself and your phone use to help you decide which, if any, of our products and services would suit you best

4\. Why We Collect Information  
We may use and analyse information about you for the following purposes:  

  * To provide you with access to parts of this site;
  * To process your order;
  * To supply services and products that you have ordered
  * To contact you if necessary and to verify that you are an authorised user for security purposes;
  * To arrange for payment of goods and/or services purchased;
  * To inform you of any service related message or of any new services or functionality (eg the introduction of a new messaging service);
  * To assist us with crime and fraud prevention;
  * To help us enhance the products and services that we offer you;
  * For the purpose of market analysis and production of internal reports, for marketing our products and services generally and (subject to any objection or preference you may indicate when submitting your details to us) for sending information to you about our products and services from time to time.
  * Informing you of any products and services offered by other companies that we think may be of interest to you, provided that you choose to receive this information. If you choose to receive information from other companies, we may sometimes disclose your personal information to those companies. See Disclosure of your information. 

**Receiving marketing information**  
If you are an O2 Portal Registered Customer, you may, at any time, change your mind about receiving information from O2 or other companies in the future. If you subsequently decide that you no longer wish to receive information about either our products and services or those of third parties, you can notify us online by clicking on "Edit My Profile" under the heading of "MyO2".  
The 'opt-in' on the website allows you to select whether you receive information from O2 only, and/or from our business partners. You can opt-out of either or both at any time. We take every effort to ensure that any data provided to our business partners, with your permission, is handled with the same attention to privacy as we take. 

5\. Disclosure of your Information  
We may disclose your information to other companies in the O2 Group of companies, including their respective partners, agents and sub contractors, for any of the above purposes. In addition, we may disclose your information as may be required by law, regulation or legal proceedings.

The information you provide to us may be passed to third parties located outside the European Economic Area. Countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have strong data protection laws. However we will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with this policy. Additional terms and conditions may be presented when signing up for specific products and services.

If you choose to receive marketing information from other companies, we will only disclose your personal information to these companies where they have undertaken not to use your personal information for any purpose other than to provide information to you or other uses to which you have agreed. If you decide that you no longer want to receive information from a particular company, you should contact that company directly. You should be aware that if you subsequently give any personal information to another company, the uses to which that information may be put would be determined by that company's privacy policy.

If you are an O2 Portal Registered Customer, any Media Messages you send to an email address, including Media Messages from your phone and messages from the O2 Portal will include your registered portal first name and last name and your phone number which will be displayed in the 'from' field of the email.

**O2 Chat rooms and Opinion Forums**  
You are reminded that chat rooms and opinion forums are for public discussion. Any personal information that you choose to supply when you participate in these discussions are widely accessible. Never reveal any personal information such as your telephone number, postal or email address when you participate in these discussions.

6\. Co-Branded Micro Sites and Third Party Sites  
Web pages and/or Micro Websites included within the website may be co-branded with third party names, logos, and/or properties. These Micro Websites are operated or maintained by O2. While such third parties are sponsors of these web pages or micro websites, the third parties do not share in any personally identifiable information collected within those web pages or Micro Websites unless otherwise stated. 

Link to Glossary

This policy does not apply to third party sites that you may access via an O2 Site. You should therefore ensure that you are familiar with the applicable third party privacy policy before entering any personal information on a third party site.

Back to Top

7\. Cookies  
A "cookie" is a piece of information, like a tag, which some websites create on your PC which identifies your PC whenever you visit that website. In order to provide you with the best possible online experience, O2 may create cookies when you visit the O2 site. Cookies may be used to help you in the following ways: to limit the frequency with which you will see particular advertisements or O2 announcements on the site; to identify your defaults if you have set up a customised homepage; to keep track of how many times you do specific things whilst using O2, to track where you have come from if you were referred to our website; to provide you with self-help information; and to make our email offers more relevant to you by taking into account your response to previous email offers.

Our cookies will not be used to analyse your visits to other sites. Agents of O2, who assist in the serving, and targeting of advertisements, promotions and other marketing messages may use cookies to collect anonymous data such as how many people have viewed a particular page each day. Data collected by cookies will not otherwise be passed to any third party. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most PCs automatically accept them but you can modify your browser settings to decline if you so wish - click here to switch off cookies on your browser. If you decline cookies, some aspects of the O2 site may not work on your PC and you may not be able to access areas you want on the website. For this reason we recommend that you accept cookies.

If you select the 'Remember Me' function, where it is available, for any return visits, you will need to have cookies enabled on your browser. 

Link to Glossary

Back to Top

8\. Accessing your Information  
As an O2 Portal Registered Customer, you have control over the accuracy of your personal information. If, at any time, you wish to verify, update or amend the personal information you have provided to O2, you can do so online by clicking on "Edit My Profile" under the heading "MyO2".  
**Access to Data**  
You can access your personal information at any time. Just make a written request clearly identifying yourself and the information you require. We'll charge you £10 to cover the administrative cost of supplying it. If we hold any inaccurate information about you, please tell us and we will correct it.   
Our address is:  
FAO: The Data Controller

O2 (UK) Limited  
260 Bath Road  
Slough  
Berkshire  
SL1 4DX 

9\. Security  
You must not share your password for any message services or Portal access. Your passwords and the answers to secret questions are your responsibility, and must not be disclosed to any third party. This is also important for your own protection.

We are constantly reviewing our procedures to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, accidental loss and/or destruction. We use industry standard secure sockets layer (SSL) technology, to encrypt sensitive information such as financial information eg your credit card  
Please be aware that communications over the Internet, such as e-mails/Webmails, are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered - this is the nature of the World Wide Web/Internet. O2 cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.  
Link to Glossary

10\. Users 16 and under  
If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission before providing any personal information or before taking part in any O2.co.uk discussion Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

Remember, never reveal any personal information about yourself or anyone else (for example, telephone number, home address or e-mail address) on chat rooms, discussion forums or bulletin boards. 

11\. Changes to this Policy  
We will keep this policy under review and any changes made from time to time will be posted on this page.  
We will notify you of any changes with a link to this privacy policy on the log-in page of this site.

Back to Top

12\. FAQS on other related issues  
a) Location information  
b) How can you avoid receiving SPAM?

**a) Location Information**

Some web and mobile telephone services that you use from your O2 mobile may require us to disclose information about the location of your mobile phone to third parties. By using location-based services such as 'Find My Nearest ATM' or 'Friend Finder', you consent to O2 disclosing your information to third parties required to provide you with the service. The information that we provide to third parties will be an approximate location only.  
However if do not wish your location to be disclosed for some or all services, please call our Location Services Privacy Controller (LSPC) by dialling 1300, free of charge from your O2 mobile (for non-O2 customers, please contact your network provider). If you have contacted the LSPC and decided to withhold your location information you may not be able to access certain services that require this information.

Link to Glossary

**Location Services Privacy Controller (LSPC)**  
You can control how the location of your mobile is used to provide you with services by dialling the LSPC on 1300, free of charge from your O2 mobile.  
You can choose a location status from the list below by following the voice prompts  
a. You can be found by all location services, including those that allow other user to find you. These services may include those such as "Find a buddy" type services where you and your friends can find each other  
b. You can be found by all location services that you use from your own mobile.  
These services will only locate you each time you use the service, by calling or sending a text message for example  
c. You can be found by all O2 location services but not by services that require your location to be disclosed to any third party services  
You cannot be found by any location services, except by the emergency services in the event that you make an emergency call from your mobile. Link to Glossary

**b) How can you avoid receiving Spam?**

**Think before you give out your e-mail address**  
Try to avoid giving your main e-mail address on web sites, chatrooms, newsgroups or to companies. There are many places online that provide free e-mail accounts. You could set up a separate account to use when signing up to an Internet service, or for online shopping. This way your main e-mail address cannot be "harvested" by spammers. Avoid forwarding chain letters or petitions. These lists of addresses can be used by spammers.

**Never reply to spam**  
This includes the notorious "click here to unsubscribe" trick. While it looks as if you are being given a chance to opt out of receiving further unsolicited e-mail, in fact you will be letting the spammer know that your e-mail address is active, leading to yet more spam being sent. Don't click it - just delete the e-mail.  
You should also avoid trying to spam the spammers, you will end up being blacklisted as a spammer yourself.

**Blocks and Filters**  
Your Webmail has simple spam blocking features already. Have a look for the pages on "spam" or "junk mail" in the 'Help' section of the Webmail service. If you are downloading emails onto your home PC, then email your Internet Service Provider or search their website to find out about spam blocking services they may offer. There are various software programs to help you block spam.

Link to Glossary

13\. Glossary  
| Internet  | The international system of interconnected computer networks utilising standard protocols and procedures to transmit electronic data.  
---|---  
O2 Portal Registered Customer | Someone who has successfully registered their details on www.o2.co.uk website. This website is only open to UK residents who own or intend to own a UK network mobile phone.  
Network | The electronic communications system by which we make Services available in the United Kingdom.  
Portals | Our web, WAP, O2 Active and XDA portals and any other services and portals we introduce from time to time.   
Media Message (MMS) (Multimedia Messaging Service) | A message that can contain text, images, video and audio.  
Micro Websites | Self- contained websites relating to a particular product eg O2 Xda or a promotion eg O2 Music, built to function independently of the main website  
Spam | Unsolicited "junk" e-mail or Messages sent to large numbers of people to promote products or services. The term also refers to inappropriate promotional or commercial postings to discussion groups or bulletin boards.  
WAP Services | Services provided via Wireless Application Protocol (a secure specification that allows users to access Content via handheld wireless devices such as mobile phones). "O2 Active"refers to those WAP Services made available to O2 Network customers directly from the O2 Active menu on your Device.  
Webmails | An email system that can be accessed via the web browser .  
Web Services | Services provided from our websitewww.o2.co.uk and any additional websites linked from our website.  
Web and WAP services terms and conditions | Terms and conditions for our Web and WAP services located on our website.
